<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>🪴 Quartz 3.3 on</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in 🪴 Quartz 3.3 on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 18:58:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup</title><link>/notes/setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/setup/</guid><description>Making your own Quartz Setting up Quartz requires a basic understanding of git. If you are unfamiliar, this resource is a great place to start!
Forking A fork is a copy of a repository. Forking a repository allows you to freely experiment with changes without affecting the original project.
Navigate to the GitHub repository for the Quartz project:
📁 Quartz Repository
Then, Fork the repository into your own GitHub account.</description></item><item><title>Editing Content in Quartz</title><link>/notes/editing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/editing/</guid><description>Editing Quartz runs on top of Hugo so all notes are written in Markdown.
Folder Structure Here&amp;rsquo;s a rough overview of what&amp;rsquo;s what.
All content in your garden can found in the /content folder. To make edits, you can open any of the files and make changes directly and save it. You can organize content into any folder you&amp;rsquo;d like.
To edit the main home page, open /content/_index.md.
Front Matter Hugo is picky when it comes to metadata for files.</description></item><item><title>Obsidian Vault Integration</title><link>/notes/obsidian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/obsidian/</guid><description>Setup Obsidian is the preferred way to use Quartz. You can either create a new Obsidian Vault or link one that your already have.
New Vault If you don&amp;rsquo;t have an existing Vault, download Obsidian and create a new Vault in the /content folder that you created and cloned during the setup step.
Linking an existing Vault The easiest way to use an existing Vault is to copy all of your files (directory and hierarchies intact) into the /content folder.</description></item><item><title>Preview Changes</title><link>/notes/preview-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/preview-changes/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;d like to preview what your Quartz site looks like before deploying it to the internet, the following instructions guide you through installing the proper dependencies to run it locally.
Install hugo-obsidian This step will generate the list of backlinks for Hugo to parse. Ensure you have Go (&amp;gt;= 1.16) installed.
1 2 # Install and link `hugo-obsidian` locally go install github.com/jackyzha0/hugo-obsidian@latest If you are running into an error saying that command not found: hugo-obsidian, make sure you set your GOPATH correctly (see [[notes/troubleshooting#command not found: hugo-obsidian|the troubleshooting page]])!</description></item><item><title>Deploying Quartz to the Web</title><link>/notes/hosting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/hosting/</guid><description>Hosting on GitHub Pages Quartz is designed to be effortless to deploy. If you forked and cloned Quartz directly from the repository, everything should already be good to go! Follow the steps below.
Enable GitHub Actions Permissions By default, GitHub disables workflows from modifying your files (for good reason!). However, Quartz needs this to write the actual site files back to GitHub.
Head to Settings &amp;gt; Action &amp;gt; General &amp;gt; Workflow Permissions and choose Read and Write Permissions</description></item><item><title>Gemz</title><link>/joplin/gemz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 18:58:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/joplin/gemz/</guid><description/></item><item><title>We Choose to go to the Moon</title><link>/joplin/we-choose-to-go-to-the-moon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 18:57:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>/joplin/we-choose-to-go-to-the-moon/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Life Explained in 27 Seconds</title><link>/joplin/life-explained-in-27-seconds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 18:57:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>/joplin/life-explained-in-27-seconds/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Unofficial Goldman Sachs Guide To Being A Man</title><link>/joplin/the-unofficial-goldman-sachs-guide-to-being-a-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 18:56:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>/joplin/the-unofficial-goldman-sachs-guide-to-being-a-man/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Flesh of Polar Codes</title><link>/joplin/the-flesh-of-polar-codes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 18:55:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>/joplin/the-flesh-of-polar-codes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>RapViz</title><link>/joplin/rapviz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 18:32:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/joplin/rapviz/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Insert Interval</title><link>/joplin/insert-interval/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:44:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>/joplin/insert-interval/</guid><description/></item><item><title>2023S Course Planning</title><link>/joplin/2023s-course-planning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 04:42:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>/joplin/2023s-course-planning/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Elegant Compression in Text (The LZ 77 Method), Computerphile</title><link>/joplin/elegant-compression-in-text-the-lz-77-method-computerphile/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 10:41:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>/joplin/elegant-compression-in-text-the-lz-77-method-computerphile/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vietnam</title><link>/joplin/vietnam/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 09:35:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/joplin/vietnam/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hong Kong</title><link>/joplin/blog/hong-kong/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 01:36:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>/joplin/blog/hong-kong/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Philippines</title><link>/joplin/philippines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 08:14:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/joplin/philippines/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Philippines, Brainstorm</title><link>/joplin/philippines-brainstorm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 09:16:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>/joplin/philippines-brainstorm/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Callouts</title><link>/notes/callouts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/callouts/</guid><description>Callout support Quartz supports the same Admonition-callout syntax as Obsidian.
This includes
12 Distinct callout types (each with several aliases) Collapsable callouts See documentation on supported types and syntax here.
Showcase [!EXAMPLE] Examples
Aliases: example
[!note] Notes
Aliases: note
[!abstract] Summaries
Aliases: abstract, summary, tldr
[!info] Info
Aliases: info, todo
[!tip] Hint
Aliases: tip, hint, important
[!success] Success</description></item><item><title>CJK + Latex Support (测试)</title><link>/notes/cjk-+-latex-support-%E6%B5%8B%E8%AF%95/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/cjk-+-latex-support-%E6%B5%8B%E8%AF%95/</guid><description>Chinese, Japanese, Korean Support 几乎在我们意识到之前，我们已经离开了地面。
우리가 그것을 알기도 전에 우리는 땅을 떠났습니다.
私たちがそれを知るほぼ前に、私たちは地面を離れていました。
Latex Block math works with two dollar signs $$...$$
$$f(x) = \int_{-\infty}^\infty f\hat(\xi),e^{2 \pi i \xi x} ,d\xi$$
Inline math also works with single dollar signs $...$. For example, Euler&amp;rsquo;s identity but inline: $e^{i\pi} = -1$
Aligned equations work quite well:
$$ \begin{aligned} a &amp;amp;= b + c \ &amp;amp;= e + f \ \end{aligned} $$
And matrices</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>/notes/config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/config/</guid><description>Configuration Quartz is designed to be extremely configurable. You can find the bulk of the configuration scattered throughout the repository depending on how in-depth you&amp;rsquo;d like to get.
The majority of configuration can be found under data/config.yaml. An annotated example configuration is shown below.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 # The name to display in the footername:Jacky Zhao# whether to globally show the table of contents on each page# this can be turned off on a per-page basis by adding this to the# front-matter of that noteenableToc:true# whether to by-default open or close the table of contents on each pageopenToc:false# whether to display on-hover link preview cardsenableLinkPreview:true# whether to render titles for code blocksenableCodeBlockTitle:true# whether to render copy buttons for code blocksenableCodeBlockCopy:true# whether to render calloutsenableCallouts:true# whether to try to process LatexenableLatex:true# whether to enable single-page-app style rendering# this prevents flashes of unstyled content and improves# smoothness of Quartz.</description></item><item><title>Custom Domain</title><link>/notes/custom-domain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/custom-domain/</guid><description>Registrar This step is only applicable if you are using a custom domain! If you are using a &amp;lt;YOUR-USERNAME&amp;gt;.github.io domain, you can skip this step.
For this last bit to take effect, you also need to create a CNAME record with the DNS provider you register your domain with (i.e. NameCheap, Google Domains).
GitHub has some documentation on this, but the tldr; is to
Go to your forked repository (github.</description></item><item><title>Hosting with Docker</title><link>/notes/docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/docker/</guid><description>If you want to host Quartz on a machine without using a webpage hosting service, it may be easier to install Docker Compose and follow the instructions below than to install Quartz&amp;rsquo;s dependencies manually.
Hosting Quartz Locally You can serve Quartz locally at http://localhost:1313 with the following script, replacing /path/to/quartz with the actual path to your Quartz folder.
docker-compose.yml
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 services: quartz-hugo: image: ghcr.</description></item><item><title>Ignoring Notes</title><link>/notes/ignore-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/ignore-notes/</guid><description>Quartz Ignore Edit ignoreFiles in config.toml to include paths you&amp;rsquo;d like to exclude from being rendered.
1 2 3 4 5 6 ... ignoreFiles = [ &amp;#34;/content/templates/*&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;/content/private/*&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;&amp;lt;your path here&amp;gt;&amp;#34; ] ignoreFiles supports the use of Regular Expressions (RegEx) so you can ignore patterns as well (e.g. ignoring all .pngs by doing \\.png$). To ignore a specific file, you can also add the tag draft: true to the frontmatter of a note.</description></item><item><title>Private Stuff</title><link>/private/private-note/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/private/private-note/</guid><description>This page doesn&amp;rsquo;t get published!</description></item><item><title>Quartz Philosophy</title><link>/notes/philosophy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/philosophy/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;[One] who works with the door open gets all kinds of interruptions, but [they] also occasionally gets clues as to what the world is and what might be important.&amp;rdquo; — Richard Hamming
Why Quartz? Hosting a public digital garden isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. There are an overwhelming number of tutorials, resources, and guides for tools like Notion, Roam, and Obsidian, yet none of them have super easy to use free tools to publish that garden to the world.</description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>/notes/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/search/</guid><description>Quartz supports two modes of searching through content.
Full-text Full-text search is the default in Quartz. It produces results that exactly match the search query. This is easier to setup but usually produces lower quality matches.
1 2 # the default optionenableSemanticSearch:false Natural Language Natural language search is powered by Operand. It understands language like a person does and finds results that best match user intent. In this sense, it is closer to how Google Search works.</description></item><item><title>Showcase</title><link>/notes/showcase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/showcase/</guid><description>Want to see what Quartz can do? Here are some cool community gardens :)
Quartz Documentation (this site!) Jacky Zhao&amp;rsquo;s Garden Scaling Synthesis - A hypertext research notebook AWAGMI Intern Notes Shihyu&amp;rsquo;s PKM SlRvb&amp;rsquo;s Site Course notes for Information Technology Advanced Theory Brandon Boswell&amp;rsquo;s Garden Siyang&amp;rsquo;s Courtyard Data Dictionary 🧠 sspaeti.com&amp;rsquo;s Second Brain oldwinterの数字花园 SethMB Work Abhijeet&amp;rsquo;s Math Wiki Mike&amp;rsquo;s AI Garden 🤖🪴 If you want to see your own on here, submit a Pull Request adding yourself to this file!</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting and FAQ</title><link>/notes/troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/troubleshooting/</guid><description>Still having trouble? Here are a list of common questions and problems people encounter when installing Quartz.
While you&amp;rsquo;re here, join our Discord :)
Does Quartz have Latex support? Yes! See CJK + Latex Support (测试) for a brief demo.
Can I use &amp;lt;Obsidian Plugin&amp;gt; in Quartz? Unless it produces direct Markdown output in the file, no. There currently is no way to bundle plugin code with Quartz.
The easiest way would be to add your own HTML partial that supports the functionality you are looking for.</description></item><item><title>Updating</title><link>/notes/updating/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/updating/</guid><description>Haven&amp;rsquo;t updated Quartz in a while and want all the cool new optimizations? On Unix/Mac systems you can run the following command for a one-line update! This command will show you a log summary of all commits since you last updated, press q to acknowledge this. Then, it will show you each change in turn and press y to accept the patch or n to reject it. Usually you should press y for most of these unless it conflicts with existing changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made!</description></item><item><title>{{title}}</title><link>/templates/post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/templates/post/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>